Subhanshu Pradhan

+91 70424 84547 subhanshu@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/subhanshup/

ABOUT

A multi-skilled solutions driven IT professional with 20-year track record of commended performance in modular and object-oriented programming. Well-versed in all phases of the software development lifecycle, with a strong working knowledge of algorithms and data structures. Certified Scrum Master with experience in implementing agile methodologies. Proven success engineering customized solutions improving business processes, operations and profitability. Able to incorporate user needs into costeffective, secure and user-friendly solutions known for scalability and durability.

Proven leader and project manager; drive system architecture decisions and lead projects from concept through the release process.

EXPERIENCE

GWInTech - Green Work Integrated Technologies Private Limited, Hyderabad/Remote

Head of Engineering | October 2020 - PRESENT

Decision Engines is an Intelligent Process Automation product, Where I was responsible for customer focused development of solutions

- Deploying and migrating dedicated kubernetes based environments across Google Cloud and Amazon Web Services.
- Heading a team of experienced developers (Python, NodeJS, Angular, Java) and devops engineers along with customer support team.
- Was Involved in pre-sales demos and hand holding of the prospective customers.
- Leading all aspects of customer support.
- Involved in devising solutions based on various AI/ML based techniques primarily involving Computer Vision, Natural Language Processing and Optical Character Recognition.
- Worked with various API's like Sales Force, Ariba, Jira etc.

Triptalker, New Delhi

Head of Engineering | April 2019 – September 2020

Responsible for the development of a new social travel platform for an existing travel company

- Heading a team of front-end and back-end programmers along with UI/UX designers
- Technology stack being used is Angular 9, PHP, WordPress, MySQL, Nginx to develop progressive web application and Ionic Framework for Mobile application.
- Google Cloud platform Kubernetes, AutoML API, Vision API, Natural Language Processing, Maps API.
- Other tools being used are MongoDB, Elastic Search, Jira, Selenium etc.
- Determining optimum cloud infrastructure with appropriate fallbacks
- Coordination with Product manager and Marketing team

TOOLS, TECHNOLOGIES & FRAMEWORK

PHP, Ruby On Rails, Microsoft
.Net(VB and C#), Java, HTML5,
CSS3, JavaScript, Android/iOS
mobile applications(Native and
Hybrid). Angular JS, WordPress,
Magento, JQuery, Bootstrap and
numerous API's(Including various
flightsearch API's) and libraries.

DATABASES

Microsoft SQL Server, Oracle, MySQL, Firebase, MongoDB.

SYSTEMS

Windows (all), Linux, Macintosh OS X, UNiX

WEB SERVERS

IIS, Apache on
Windows/Linux/Mac, NodeJS

SKILLS / INDUSTRY KNOWLEDGE

Software Architecture.

Product Development.

SaaS.

Authentication Systems,

Infrastructure and engineering design.

DevOps.

Database management.

System, platform, and account migrations

Data and cloud security

Azure cloud infrastructure

Web and Mobile platforms.

Project and product management.

Enterprise Architecture frameworks.

Business acumen.

RL Travel Ltd., New Delhi

IT Lead | February 2018 - March 2019

Leading a team of programmers developing B2B Air Ticket booking portal for RL Group to be used by their agents for bookings and accounting.

- Designing the architecture of B2B Air Ticket booking portal for RL Group to be used for using various flight API's.
- Integration and syndication of various flight API's with the intention of reselling them to other OTA's.

EXL SERVICES, New Delhi

Manager-Operations Technology | APRIL 2017 - JULY 2017

Client: Fursan Travel and Tourism co.

Responsible for client's IT Infrastructure with onsite and cloud servers, desktops on Microsoft Windows platform with Active Directory, SQL Servers, MySQL Servers, Linux/Apache Servers. Also included was maintenance of all applications of the organization.

- Co-ordination between the EXL and Fursan Teams for successful rebadging of employees to EXL from Fursan. This also included making relevant changes to IT Infrastructure and security setup at both ends.
- Successfully migrated Applications from AWS cloud to Microsoft Azure. The project included migration of Windows AD, MS SQL 2005/2008 and Application servers.
- Successfully migrated Applications from Google Cloud to Microsoft Azure. The project included migration of Linux servers with Apache, MySQL and PHP.
- Security audit of Fursan Travel and Tourism co. and implementation of security best practices.
- Implementation of Microsoft BI Infrastructure on Azure cloud to be used by the BI Team of Fursan.
- Troubleshoot the IT Infrastructure and recommended improvements to infrastructure.

Fursan Travel & Tourism Co., New Delhi Manager-Web Development | FEBRUARY 2016 - MARCH 2017

Leading application support and development across the organization and maintaining IT infrastructure spread across various providers.

- Managing all the in-house and external web applications and developing the new ones as per the requirements.
- Management of Servers spread across the companies own data centre,
 Amazon Web Services, Google Cloud and Microsoft Azure.
- Successfully migrated Applications from corporate office to AWS cloud. The project included migration of Windows AD, MS SQL 2005/2008 and Application servers.
- Migrated email from MS Exchange Server to Google Apps for business.
- Designed, programmed and deployed closed group web application to be used for information dissemination and collaboration among the

CERTIFICATIONS

Certified Ethical Hacker from EC Council

Certified Scrum Master from Scrum Alliance

EDUCATION

C.C.S University, Meerut

BBA (Marketing) - 2000

CBSE Board, Meerut

Intermediate - March 1996

INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Cross-Functional Team Leadership

Bias for Action

Team Building

Management

Focused

Attention to detail

Goal orientated

LANGUAGES

English, Hindi

- employees of the organization
- Created and implemented customer data acquisition application based on Angular JS, Firebase.
- Created and Implemented internal cab booking application using PHP, Angular JS, Linux, MySQL.
- Co-ordination with vendor's/service providers.
- Implement security and integrity in operational environment to meet PCI standards.
- Helpdesk Setup for incident management (ITIL V3).

VNC Systems, Gurgaon

Head(Software Development) | AUGUST-2005 - JANUARY 2016

Leading application support and development across the organization and maintaining IT infrastructure spread across various providers.

- Reengineered multiple systems that fuelled improvements to productivity, efficiency, uptime and accuracy for global business operations. Developed code, system design and test/QA plans for all solutions and often coordinated the national or international rollout.
- Led, architected and participated in the design, testing and deployment of client/server, multitier applications, Web Applications including Single Page Applications and Responsive Designs, Mobile Applications, ActiveX and related components.
- Developed new procedures for requirements gathering, needs analysis, testing, scripting and documentation to strengthen quality and functionality of business-critical applications.
- Developed large-scale, portable, thread-safe and ultra-high performance foundation and application infrastructure libraries.
- Trained and mentored programmers in programming methodologies and best practices.
- Delivered back-office tools supporting ecommerce initiatives, enabling company to compete more effectively in the marketplace through search-engine optimization.
- Served as a core group member in defining and prioritizing technology investments for the next two years, ensuring the alignment of process, technology and business objectives.

Manoware Technologies, Delhi

PROJECT MANAGER | APRIL-2004 - AUGUST 2005

S.N. Computers, Meerut

TEAM LEADER | JUNE-2000 - MARCH 2004